now that we have seen all the steps in
tomasulo's algorithm let's take a moment
and review the whole thing this is our
instruction queue our rad register
aliasing table the registers themselves
and let's say we only have the two
reservation stations for the add
subtract unit to make this more compact
if we look at the steps that happen for
one instruction here's what we have we
take the instruction from the
instruction queue and issue it to a
reservation station and we look up the
rat to tell us where the operands for
the instruction are going to come from
now that the instruction has been issued
it sits in its reservation station and
waits for the operands to actually
become ready during that time the
instruction is trying to capture the
results broadcast by other instructions
that are executing once we have captured
the last operon that we were missing the
instruction will dispatch which means it
is sent for execution and when it's done
executing it writes its result which
means now this instruction will
broadcast its result this is used by
other instructions to capture their
missing operands this instruction also
writes to the register that it is
supposed to update and it updates the
right for that register so that future
instructions start reading the register
file and not waiting for this
instruction anymore what is important to
note is that although these happen one
at a time for one instruction every
cycle some instruction may be in one of
these steps so during a particular cycle
some instruction might be issued some
instructions are trying to capture their
operands some instructions are trying to
be dispatched and finally some
instruction is writing its result and
that is the result that is being
captured by the instructions that are
trying to capture so all of this
activity is happening during every cycle
is
just it is happening for different
instructions so you can look at each of
these steps needs to be taken by a
particular instruction but the processor
doesn't do just an issue of an
instruction in a cycle it's doing the
issue for that instruction while trying
to capture for others while trying to
dispatch another while doing the right
result for yet another instruction